# Fernando Arriagada

Senior Front-End Developer

Santiago, Chile (GMT-3) (+56) 9 99412410 farriagadal94@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/fernando-arriagada https://farriagadal.site

Senior Front-End Developer with +5 years of experience in the area of software development with Javascript and Typescript (React.js, Vue.js and Angular). I have worked in technology consulting companies, marketing agencies and start-ups. I have solid knowledge in development technologies such as Docker, Git, Jira, AWS. I am motivated by researching and reading about science and technology. I am constantly developing my own projects.

# **EXPERIENCE**

## NTTDATA, Senior Front-End Developer — March, 2022 - Present

- I developed and led an application in React.js for Falabella Retail. I supervised two junior developers and we made sure to meet deadlines, code quality and documentation in Confluence. We optimized load by 80% on the pages with the highest demand and received very positive feedback from the client.
- I led a proof of concept project with LATAM Airlines to integrate Google Looker with React.js and display information on dashboards. The project lasted 1 month and I supervised 2 Jr. developers. The contract was renewed with LATAM Airlines and NTT DATA for future enhancements.
- I led the Front-End development of a web platform in React.js for administration and management of medical staff of "Clinica Las Condes". The team consisted of 2 Front-end developers and 2 Back-end developers. I was in charge of meeting deadlines and maintaining code quality.
- I was in charge of performing unit tests for a web application for the client "Clínica Alemana". I increased the coverage of Unit Tests by 60%, in 2 weeks, which significantly improved the code quality and reduced the amount of bugs.

Technology Stack: React.js, Next.js, Jest.

## MEAT Group, Semi-Senior Front-End Developer — September, 2020 - March, 2022

- I developed a web platform for monitoring and evaluation of branches of the company "THE LINE". The project was developed with React.js and used the "Jest" library for unit testing.
- I led the development of a web platform for ticket sales for the "Teatro Municipal de Santiago", where I was in charge of developing the Front-end and the integration with the API for ticket sales. The project lasted 6 months and was done with the Nuxt.js framework for SEO optimization.
- I developed a Wordpress plugin for the website of the company "Redragon", which had the purpose of managing all the locations of their stores on a map. The plugin was developed using the "Open Street Maps" library which replaced the paid "Mapbox" plugin, saving a significant cost due to the high traffic of the website.
- Maintenance of Banco de Chile App in Vue.js and compilation for mobile devices (Android and iOS) with Cordova
- Other developments and maintenance of websites and web apps.
  Technology Stack: Vue.js, Nuxt.js, React.js, Docker, Wordpress, Laravel, Cordova.

#### Opting IT Solutions, Software Engineer — September, 2018 - June, 2020

- I collaborated in the development of "Planify", a venture of "Opting". It consisted of a SAAS for the construction industry to help manage tasks and improve communication between the different disciplines that interact in a construction site.
- I led an agile cell as Scrum Master in charge of 3 developers for more than 1 year. I maintained a close relationship with clients to define objectives, and presentation of weekly progress.
- I worked training 3 Jr. developers, assigning tasks, suggesting courses and reviewing code together.
- I was in charge of the project "Totem Co" (space management system with NFC) for the client "Universidad San Sebastián".
- I collaborated in the development of an ecommerce for Ecomoa (cosmetics company), which was developed in Wordpress. The project lasted 2 months with a team of 2 full-stack developers and 1 designer. The ecommerce collected more than 5 million Chilean pesos per month in 2020.
- I helped in the development of a web platform to manage the payments and commissions of the workers of a Call Center company.

Technological stack: Angular 10, Docker, Wordpress, Python, PostgreSQL.

# GTD Consulting Engineers, Memorist — January, 2018 - April, 2018

• I developed a mathematical algorithm in Python for the automation of earthwork surveys. After conducting an investigation, it was concluded that the work hours invested by an engineer were reduced from 8 hours to 15 minutes. The software was used in several future projects with excellent results.

Technological stack: Python, GIS.

## **SKILLS**

Programming languages: Advanced: Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS; Intermediate: Python. Básico: PHP.

Frameworks: Advanced: React.js, Vue.js, Next.js; Intermediate: Angular, Django.

Databases: Intermediate: MySQL, PostgreSQL; Basic: MongoDB.

**Other Tools:** Git, Trello, Jira, Confluence, Slack, AWS. **Languages: Intermediate**: Inglés; **Native**: Español.

# **EDUCATION**

University San Sebastián – Santiago, Chile. Software Engineer, February 2018.

University San Sebastián - Santiago, Chile. Bachelor of Science in Engineering, February 2015.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Course of Advanced React.js – Platzi, Educational technology company. 2021.

Course of Testing with Vue.js – Platzi, Educational technology company. 2021.

Introduction to Python programming – Universidad Católica de Chile. 2020.

Programming with JavaScript ED6 – Movistar Chile. 2020.

Scrum Master Accredited Certification – International Scrum Institute. 2020.